October 13th, Stellar Year 2148
We can't possibly make it
across this, can we?
Of course not.
What, are we talking
about our Juggernauts?
There are all kinds of little gaps in the cockpits.
The water will come flooding right in.
Well, Haruto, Daiya, or Kujo
might've just jumped in.
Right?
Man, it's been a long three days.
With all those recon units out,
it was bound to be tough.
But we were able to keep the wind and rain off,
which was a big help.
We've been out on this special recon mission
for what, two weeks?
We've lasted longer than I thought.
I assumed we'd die on the first day.
Right?
So, where are we?
No idea. We shut off our location trackers
a long time ago.
So this is freedom, huh?
So what's the plan?
If we want to go forward,
we need to use a bridge.
But those recon units might come back.
Well,
do we really need to go forward right now?
That's right.
I'd like to do the wash.
And we're not in a big hurry.
It feels like...
we're the last people left alive.
What?
"If the last thing I see is this,
then maybe that's not so bad." Was that it?
How long ago was that?
I never took you for a romantic.
Shut up.
I don't think they're dead,
but when they die, they just disappear.
Their mind, their will...
They don't stay behind.
Like the ones that went before us?
Yes.
How many are there, now?
576.
Including your brother?
Yes.
I see.
Hey, what about his name?
Did you leave it?
Yeah.
When?
Fido knows.
You two really are close.
Now it's just a question of
how far we can take them.
Without resupply, there's a limit
to how long we can keep going.
In other words,
how many days we can survive.
Right.
Anything you're going to regret?
The Major asked you once, right?
If there was anything you wanted to do,
places you wanted to go,
things you wanted to see.
You said—
What did I say?
That you'd never even thought about it.
Then my answer's still the same.
I see.
We finally got to do the wash.
All we really need now is a big barrel
or something to put some water in.
What are you talking about?
What is it, Fido?
If you're talking about your container,
we might be able to compensate
for the lousy welding by patching it with cloth,
but we can't heat the amount of water
it would take to fill that thing.
We don't have the fuel.
I know we all miss baths,
but I don't see how it's possible.
How can you understand him that well?
There's a town nearby?
Well, I won't stop you from looking.
Seriously, how can you tell?
Is it okay, Shin? Taking a bath...
We're not going anywhere in particular.
And we should be in
old Imperial territory by now.
I'd like to see what their towns were like.
Kurena, hurry!
Okay!
Sorry, I'm ready.
No worries.
They look like ordinary kids,
walking together like that.
Anything good?
Something that would've looked good on you.
Well, the same goes for me.
We were all just ordinary kids
from different towns.
Without the war, we never would've met.
The Giadian Empire...
Does it bring back any memories for you?
No. My parents were born in Giadian,
but I've never been here before.
I don't really remember my parents at all.
It just seems like a strange place to me.
What about you?
Well, some really distant ancestors of mine,
but it's not our homeland, either, is it?
What is it?
Don't run off on your own.
You're not a little kid.
It's nothing. We're probably fine.
They haven't noticed us,
and we're not going to run into them.
You mean the Legion?
Yeah.
You tired?
If you want to rest,
that pillbox is a pretty good hiding spot.
I think it's safe to relax a bit.
Hey...
Sorry.
I told you. I'm used to
hearing the Legion's voices.
There are more voices now that
we're inside their territory, but it's not that bad.
You say that, but...
There you are!
Don't get lost! Are you little kids?
Oh, are we interrupting?
Look, look! Fido found something!
Since we're not fighting,
it's easier now, actually.
Don't worry.
Roger.
It's so warm!
Kurena, if you're too loud,
the Legion will find you.
It feels good, though!
And it's probably going to cool off, too.
The boys should've joined in.
That's why, you know...
The reason you always get treated
like a little sister.
I'm not a little sister!
If we all got in together,
we could wash each other off!
It would be efficient and hygienic, right?
Are you maybe saying that deliberately?
"Deliberately"?
You don't know what that word means?
Shin, why do you think Kurena never matured?
Is it something you can eat?
Is it yummy?
I have no idea.
I'm glad we were able to take a bath.
It's thanks to Fido finding that boiler.
The Imperials ran off and left the fuel.
Nine years later and it's still usable.
They were using the good stuff.
Thanks to that,
we were able to enjoy a bath.
Good job finding it, Fido.
I don't think I've ever seen him
sleeping that peacefully.
He's been laughing a lot lately.
Yeah. It's like his expression is...
Softer now.
He's telling more jokes.
And playing along with Raiden's
and my dumb comments.
I'm sure he's at peace,
now that he's finally achieved his goal.
His brother?
He spent five years looking for him
before finally putting him to rest.
And being free.
And at the very end, he finally found someone
he could entrust himself to.
"We're going on ahead, Major," was it?
Our Reaper was lonely, wasn't he?
Having all his comrades die before him
and being forced to carry them.
So it was good for him,
being able to leave those words behind.
It kind of ticks me off, though.
It's good, but...
But?
It feels like he has nothing left.
October 14th, Stellar Year 2148
A little, anyway.
That idiot!
His Juggernaut's still here.
He didn't go on without us.
But he took his rifle and handgun.
What about the Para-RAID?
He turned it off right away.
Any idea where he might've gone, Fido?
Maybe there?
It's a zoo.
Why?
Don't ask me.
But we don't have any better options.
This is...
They're kind of like us.
Shin!
What are you doing?
It's fine, Raiden.
There's no danger.
It can't move at all.
I could tell it was approaching us,
little by little, for a while now.
It didn't seem to be a scout,
and we were going in different directions,
so I was going to ignore it.
But it felt like it was calling me.
Since yesterday.
Calling you? Then it's...
An Eighty-Six, just like us.
We can't communicate,
but I can hear its voice.
So, what's it saying?
What are its last words?
"I want to go home."
It's okay.
You can go home now.
Raiden, if there are any other surviving countries
besides the Republic...
I've heard that story a few times.
Beyond the old borders, beyond Legion territory,
there are places where the Legion don't go.
You mean if there are any survivors there?
Yeah.
You want to go there and live in peace?
I couldn't even imagine what that'd be like.
In a fairy tale, journeys like this end
with you arriving in paradise.
Paradise? Or heaven?
If I could count on something like that,
I would've blown my own head off ages ago.
Are we going to die like this, too?
"Stop talking and go forward," is that it?
You're being bossy, Fido!
What is Fido, really?
He's not just a dog that beeps, right?
Are you...
going to the other side
of the water alone?
Never mind. Let's go.
You're still alive?
The squadron, your friends...
They're all gone, but...
Even so...
Will you go back with me?
This is your new pigsty.
You've got six months left.
Work hard until the very last minute, Eighty-Six.
You're the last one. Come on.
Look this way, pig.
Wow!
What do you think you're doing?
Can I ask you a favor?
So you're the Reaper's buddy, huh?
Stay with him until the end, okay?
Yes!
No! Wipe that off, you stupid kid.
You know what this means?
I bet you don't!
When I tripped today, Shin grabbed me.
His hand touched my back!
Did you see?
Fido, I have a question for you.
Do you know which tastes worst?
A machine wouldn't know.
How did he know?
It's so bad
that even Fido can tell, huh?
I don't know how we ate that stuff.
Fido, those parts that came in yesterday...
Hey!
That's right now. No meaning at all.
The stars, the sky, the wind...
They've got nothing to do with any of us.
They're just there and always have been.
You understand that?
Fido, you get it, right?
I just wanted to take a peek!
That's right. Fido gets it.
Wait, is Fido a guy?
You like pretty flowers?
Are you a little girl?
No, I guess boys can like flowers, too.
My favorite flower is...
Shin paid me a compliment today!
We were fighting and then...
Seeing them will change your life!
"Change your life"?
You can't change your life that easily.
Right?
Fido, the aurora!
Let's set off for the north pole!
Well, you can't change your life
that easily, though.
But something will change.
Do you think
I can change things for her?
What can I do for him?
So, I want you to survive until then.
A special recon mission
with the five of them would be a ton of fun.
You'll come along, right?
Right?
I'm amazed I've made it this far.
I wonder if I'll be next.
This time, I'll die, right?
Thank you for everything.
Keep them safe.
I'm happy for you.
Everybody smile!
This'll be the last photo you ever take!
Three,
two,
one!
Yeah.
Thank you.
October 30th, Stellar Year 2148
"Here we go."